It was an age of war.
Relying on only his own skill,
one man wandered the land.
A samurai.
This man is not
a wandering samurai of today.
All done!
What's next?
I found this while cleaning.
Your violin...
Yes, back when I was in middle school,
I went to that violin school
in Takadanobaba.
You really played?
What do you mean?
Oh, nothing.
Yamada!
I miss those days.
Wow.
Hashed beef and rice.
I'm going out.
Where to?
We aren't even close to being done.
After retiring, he lost his title
as a corporate man
and the support of his company.
Takeshi Kasumi, 60 years old.
This story
is about a normal 60-year-old man,
who is helped by a masterless samurai,
eating freely without being held back.
A gourmet fantasy.
I got the urge to visit a restaurant...
I often went to as a student.
It was next to an inn,
and served Western food.
RESTAURANT KARUIZAWA
It was a small restaurant,
owned and operated by a husband and wife.
The menu had a variety
of Western dishes.
Everything was delicious,
but I especially liked
their hashed beef rice.
Welcome.
Here's a menu.
TAKADANOBABA STATION
A MEMORY OF HASHED BEEF AND RICE
I want the hashed beef rice
from that restaurant.
SAKAEDORI SHOPPING STREET
I'm not exaggerating
when I say its flavor was one of a kind.
After getting a job,
I tried it at many restaurants,
but none came close.
I'm revisiting the beloved taste
from my youth.
It's a little dramatic, isn't it?
You could say...
I'm like a stoic samurai
who walks slowly
and confidently along a long road.
A journey to visit
the swordmaster who taught him
the way of the samurai.
What?
Am I lost?
This way, maybe.
No, that way.
Shoot.
I'm getting lost even more.
DYE SHOP KOSHUYA,
ASAKUSA
That shop...
Around that corner...
is where the restaurant should be.
It's supposed to be here.
Well, it has been 40 years.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Wasn't there a restaurant near here
called Karuizawa?
Restaurant Karuizawa
changed location last spring.
Changed location? Where to?
If I remember correctly,
somewhere near Okachimachi.
Okachimachi?
Yes!
All right, I'm off!
I was a bit like
an investigative detective back there.
Good grief.
Where could he have gone now?
Thank you for this meal.
OKACHIMACHI STATION
It should be around here.
But with just the station's name,
finding it won't be easy.
-Excuse me.
-Yes?
Do you know of a nearby
Western-style restaurant named Karuizawa?
-Karuizawa?
-Yes.
-I'm sorry, I don't know.
-That's okay. Thank you.
The restaurant's name may have changed.
KARUIZAWA
LUNCH MENU
I found it!
Karuizawa.
-I really wanted to come here today.
-Really?
-Here is your chicken sauté.
-Thank you.
Welcome!
Please have a seat.
Okay.
Thanks for coming.
Here is a menu.
Thank you.
RESTAURANT KARUIZAWA
A LA CARTE MENU
There it is.
-Excuse me.
-Yes?
A large hashed beef rice.
Understood.
I'll take your menu.
One large hashed beef rice.
I feel just like I did back then.
The butter smells so good.
Flounder meunière.
Your fried shrimp is on the way.
I had meunière for the first time
at this restaurant as well.
It was also amazing.
It's so good!
Thank you for the meal.
This is it!
Beef and big onion pieces
are the only main ingredients.
And the color, the aroma...
Nothing has changed.
It's the hashed beef rice I loved.
This is the best.
I've never been good at eating
hashed beef rice evenly.
I always finish the hashed beef first.
Well, what now?
You're the student who always
ate hashed beef rice.
You came here often, didn't you?
You remember me?
You always had extra rice left over,
and ate it with the pickled vegetables.
You're pretty unique.
Oh, dear.
Everyone has their own mannerisms
and habits when they eat.
And they don't change.
Their posture when they eat...
the way they use their utensils...
the way they open their mouth
and chew their food.
Oh, do you not
-eat your rice with the pickles anymore?
-Yes, I do!
Great!
This, too, is a flavor from my youth.
-Thank you for coming.
-Thank you for the meal.
-It was delicious.
-Thank you. Please come again.
That's my son.
Oh, really?
That picture board was
at the old place as well.
Indeed.
I still have all the old pictures.
Care to see?
-Yes, please.
-Okay.
We often came here
for our school club parties.
-And all the girls liked the food here.
-Thank you.
-We had birthday parties, too.
-Yes.
Also, we had local businesses'
welcome and going-away parties.
Oh, that's right.
We also held music recitals here!
Oh, yeah, it was like a music venue.
Excuse me for a moment.
That's me!
There I am again!
I'm in a lot of these.
Shizuko.
No way.
It's Shizuko.
We happened to be
at the same place 40 years ago.
Say, "cheese!"
-Okay!
-Take ours, too!
You want your photo taken? Okay.
-Get over here!
-Hurry up.
-Hey! Get off me!
-Ready? Here we go.
Say, "cheese!"
-Okay?
-Okay! Thank you!
The flavor from my youth,
is the same as Shizuko's.
When I was working,
I took the same route to work every day
and never thought anything of it.
But now...
I see the value in taking a detour.
Takeshi Kasumi,
60 years old.
Many more destinations
await me.
Shizuko.
Shizuko!
Where have you been?
I went to the restaurant, Karuizawa.
-Karuizawa?
-Yes!
It used to be in Takadanobaba,
but they moved it to Okachimachi.
The hashed beef rice
hasn't changed at all!
Shizuko, you won't believe it.
There's a picture
of you when you were in middle school
and me when I was in college.
We are in the same picture!
We were in the same place
at the same time!
Isn't that amazing?
-That's amazing!
-Right?
As if I would say that.
Do you think that'll make me forget you
left in the middle of cleaning?
It's such a moving story.
You don't need to be like that.
What's wrong with you?
This is...
where I need to draw the line.
Do not interfere with a man's business.
A woman follows quietly behind!
What are you talking about?
Nothing.
You left everything to me to do.
Do you have any idea
how difficult it was?
That was inconsiderate of me.
Where are you going?
I'm going to stay with my parents.
No, please.
I'm joking.
I've decided we're eating out tonight.
I won't be happy until I've been
treated to a nice meal.
Hurry up. Let's go.
Okay.
I've got a long way to go
before I'm a samurai.
Subtitle translation by
Jeffrey Hales